<elements>
	<element name="Furybound Primal" type="Archetype" source="Lost Knights Homebrew" id="ID_CUSTOM_PUGL_ARCHETYPE_FURYBOUND_PRIMAL">
		<supports>Fight Club</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Deep within your blood lies the echo of a feral ancestor—a towering beast of unmatched strength and fury. You have awakened this primal essence and forged a bond with it, allowing you to transform your body into a weregorilla-like form when the fight demands it. Your rage is your strength. Your fists are the storm.</p>
			<div element="ID_CUSTOM_PUGL_FEATURE_FURYBOUND_TRANSFORMATION"/>
			<div element="ID_CUSTOM_PUGL_FEATURE_TITANIC_MIGHT"/>
			<div element="ID_CUSTOM_PUGL_FEATURE_APEX_FORM"/>
			<div element="ID_CUSTOM_PUGL_FEATURE_PRIMAL_FINISHER"/>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Furybound Primal - Embrace your inner beast with feral transformations and overpowering strength.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CUSTOM_PUGL_FEATURE_FURYBOUND_TRANSFORMATION" level="3"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CUSTOM_PUGL_FEATURE_TITANIC_MIGHT" level="6"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CUSTOM_PUGL_FEATURE_APEX_FORM" level="11"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CUSTOM_PUGL_FEATURE_PRIMAL_FINISHER" level="17"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Furybound Transformation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Lost Knights Homebrew" id="ID_CUSTOM_PUGL_FEATURE_FURYBOUND_TRANSFORMATION">
		<description>
			<p>At 3rd level, you can unleash the beast within. As a bonus action, you undergo a transformation for 1 minute. While transformed:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You gain +1 AC (stacks with Iron Chin).</li>
				<li>You can reroll 1s on unarmed damage rolls.</li>
				<li>The first time you miss with an unarmed strike each turn, you may make one additional unarmed strike.</li>
				<li>After taking the Attack action, you may spend 2 moxie points to make three unarmed strikes as a bonus action.</li>
			</ul>
			<p>You must finish a short or long rest before using this feature again.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Bonus Action">
			<description>Transform for 1 minute. Gain +1 AC, reroll 1s on unarmed damage, get a free strike on first miss per turn, and spend 2 moxie to make three bonus unarmed strikes after taking the Attack action.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Titanic Might" type="Archetype Feature" source="Lost Knights Homebrew" id="ID_CUSTOM_PUGL_FEATURE_TITANIC_MIGHT">
		<description>
			<p>At 6th level, you gain the ability to briefly channel your full beastial strength. As a bonus action, you can spend 2 moxie points to gain the following benefits for 1 minute:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Your melee weapon and unarmed attacks deal an extra 1d4 damage.</li>
				<li>You have advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.</li>
				<li>You count as one size larger for carrying, pushing, pulling, and grappling.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>Spend 2 moxie to gain 1d4 bonus melee damage, advantage on Strength checks and saves, and count as one size larger for grappling etc. (1 min).</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Apex Form" type="Archetype Feature" source="Lost Knights Homebrew" id="ID_CUSTOM_PUGL_FEATURE_APEX_FORM">
		<description>
			<p>At 11th level, while Furybound Transformation is active, your size increases by one category (to a maximum of Large). If there is insufficient room, grow to the maximum possible size. While enlarged:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Your reach increases by 5 feet.</li>
				<li>You gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical sources.</li>
			</ul>
			<p>When your transformation ends, you gain one level of exhaustion.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>While transformed, you become one size larger, gain 5 ft reach, resistance to B/P/S damage (nonmagical). One level of exhaustion when it ends.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Primal Finisher" type="Archetype Feature" source="Lost Knights Homebrew" id="ID_CUSTOM_PUGL_FEATURE_PRIMAL_FINISHER">
		<description>
			<p>At 17th level, you can unleash a devastating finisher. Once per long rest, when a creature is below half HP and within 10 feet, you can use your action and spend 5 moxie points to attempt a brutal takedown.</p>
			<ul>
				<li>The target makes a Strength saving throw (DC = 8 + proficiency bonus + Strength mod).</li>
				<li>On a failure, it takes 10d10 force damage and is knocked prone and stunned until the end of its next turn.</li>
				<li>On a success, it takes half damage and is not stunned.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Action">
			<description>Spend 5 moxie to attempt a takedown on a below-half HP creature within 10 ft. DC = 8 + prof + STR. 10d10 force damage on fail (plus prone & stun); half on success.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>
