<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Aasmodai</name>
        <description>5e homebrew</description>
        <author url="https://github.com/xLMG2BLAZEDx/custom-classes/edit/main/race-aasmodai.xml">xLMG2Blazed</author>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="race-aasmodai.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/xLMG2Blazed/custom-classes/refs/heads/main/race-aasmodai.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

    <element name="Aasmodai" type="Race" source="Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_RACE_AASMODAI">
        <description>
            <h4>PHYSICAL DESCRIPTION</h4>
            <p>Aasmodai are the offspring of celestial and infernal bloodlines, embodying divine grace and infernal power in one form. With radiant eyes, shadowed wings, and skin that flickers between light and flame, they inspire awe and fear in equal measure. Most Aasmodai stand tall and proud, with glowing tattoos or markings representing their dual nature.</p>
            <h4>SOCIETY</h4>
            <p>Aasmodai are rare and often solitary, not fitting into traditional celestial or fiendish orders. Many are driven by a desire to define their own purpose, often becoming warriors, scholars, or prophets. Their struggle to balance divine judgment and infernal passion defines their worldview.</p>
            <h4>TRAITS</h4>
            <p>
                <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span> Your Constitution score increases by 2, and one other ability score of your choice increases by 1.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Age.</span>Aasmodai mature at a similar rate to humans and live up to 120 years.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Alignment.</span>Aasmodai tend toward neutrality, pulled between two extremes.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Size.</span>You are Medium.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Speed.</span>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Darkvision.</span>You can see in dim light within 60 feet as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Infernal Resilience.</span>You have resistance to necrotic damage.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Innate Magic.</span>You know the sacred flame and fire bolt cantrips. Constitution is your spellcasting ability for these spells.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Martial Balance.</span>You are proficient in simple and martial weapons.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Divine Duality (1/Long Rest each).</span>You can undergo one of two transformations per long rest, each lasting 1 minute:<br/>
                <b>Angelic Transformation:</b> emit bright light in 60 ft, unarmed strikes deal radiant damage, flying speed of 30 ft, resistance to radiant and necrotic.<br/>
                <b>Demonic Transformation:</b> breath weapon (15 ft cone, 3d6 fire, Dex save), flying speed of 30 ft, resistance to fire and necrotic.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Religious Intuition.</span>You are proficient in the Religion skill.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Languages.</span>You can speak, read, and write Common, Celestial, and Infernal.<br/>
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="constitution" value="2"/>
            <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base"/>
            <stat name="darkvision" value="60" bonus="racial"/>
            <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_CELESTIAL" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_INFERNAL" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Skill Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_RELIGION" />
            <!-- Optional: Cantrip and transformation logic would be added here for tool integration -->
        </rules>
    </element>
</elements>
